<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chapters on Originathan</title>
    <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chapters on Originathan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.originathan.com/chapters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter1/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s docs layout for publishing online courses, software documentation, and tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter2/</guid>
      <description>Something was terribly wrong. Nick’s head was imploding in a massive bear trap of pain. Waves of nausea threatened to spill his stomach. Vertigo tore away all references. He screamed, surprised to hear his voice. &amp;ldquo;This is far more violent than I thought it would be,&amp;rdquo; rolling to his side he heaved the contents of his stomach. He practiced his breathing to try to stave off the panic. &amp;ldquo;This can&amp;rsquo;t be how I go,&amp;rdquo; he grimaced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter3/</guid>
      <description>Danny took a long look at his grandson. The last two weeks have been amazing. He thought of the first time they had met. His long-estranged daughter had contacted him a few years back. The memories forced a grin as he explored his feelings. His daughter had learned that he&amp;rsquo;d move to Oregon from California and called out of the blue. She&amp;rsquo;d been so defensive, and somehow desperate for a connection with them at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter4/</guid>
      <description>Nick followed his grandfather into the cabin, the dogs pushing past them through the entrance. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m gonna go get washed up, you need in the John before I do?&amp;rdquo;
Danny waved him off, &amp;ldquo;no sir, by all means, help yourself,&amp;rdquo; he retorted chuckling.
Nick had the hot water streaming over his shoulders in no time. The mineral &amp;ldquo;hard water&amp;rdquo; had a dry feeling on his skin. The smell was a familiar memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter5/</guid>
      <description>Nick woke to the sound of howling wind. The cabin creaked and flexed like an old boat on the water. He rolled over to look at the glowing red digits of the clock on the nightstand. 5:22, shifting to lay on his back toying with the idea of returning to sleep. A few lazy stretches later Nick tossed the blankets aside and sprung out of bed. After taking a moment to dress he stepped into the hall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter6/</guid>
      <description>Carter Bertram Holland looked at his partner, Sonny Pera. Sonny was everything that Holland was not. They were of similar builds, but that was the extent of the likeness. Sonny had a nervous energy and was prone to constant fidgeting. He was impulsive and sloppy, but he was white. His family had deep ties to the agency, which explained how he had managed to squeak by.
Sonny was out at the end of the drive waving the sheriff onto the dirt road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 7</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter7/</guid>
      <description>The steady thrum of the bus engine gave way to lulls and crescendos. The gentle side to side rocking ceased as the bus began a series of starts and stops that woke Nick from his nap. The college area of downtown Portland was rolling by on the other side of the glass.
The midnight streets of 1984 looked empty and sad. The city of 2040 superimposed over every view. The effect created a surreal landscape of an aging and outdated ghost town.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 8</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Jack, Jack. The pleasure was all mine!&amp;rdquo; Pera looked at the glassy shine in his companion&amp;rsquo;s eyes. The neon lights hanging behind him in the window of the bar reflecting their glow in the watery orbs. &amp;ldquo;We need people like you at the Agency,&amp;rdquo; he concluded. &amp;ldquo;Agent Pera, don&amp;rsquo;t bullshit me, dude. The Airforce already did that once.&amp;rdquo; The big guy swayed a little, then continued. &amp;ldquo;They screwed me! Said I didn&amp;rsquo;t have what it took to be in the space program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 9</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter9/</guid>
      <description>Holland sat down in what had become his favorite chair. He opened his folder of notes and prepared to go over the last two weeks. Winter rain crackled against the narrow window at the end of the table. He stared into the grey morning then pried his attention away and onto work. Holland pulled out the first paper-clipped bundle of files. There was nothing useful in the wiretap transcripts at first glance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 10</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter10/</guid>
      <description>Nicholas lay awake with a sheen of sweat covering his body despite the chill falling off the windows. Every swallow was tight in his throat and produced too much saliva. Tomorrow was January 2, 1985, and he would have to return to school. He&amp;rsquo;d been lying here in bed unable to think of anything else for hours. Sleep eluded him.
The previous week was a blur. Jack had not come home for several days following the family movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter11/</guid>
      <description>Sonny watched Holland pouring over his notes, he lifted his eyes to glance across the table. &amp;ldquo;Have you made the necessary preparations with Jack Starr?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You mean for tomorrow?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Yes, I mean for tomorrow. We have two technicians and a doctor arriving in the morning. It would be more than embarrassing if the subject was otherwise unavailable.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m picking Jack up myself, and before you say anything I told him I&amp;rsquo;d be there at nine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter12/</guid>
      <description>Nick was back at the library. He had been coming every morning for the last week. In the evenings he had been picking up shifts at the Market Plaza. Now he stared unseeing at the stack of index cards and loose papers on the table in front of him. He felt a heavy bone-deep fatigue that threatened to drag him under the table.
The first few days after getting his GED had been good, he had accomplished something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 13</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter13/</guid>
      <description>Holland stood looking down at the street from the window in the conference room. He could see Sonny seated on the edge of the desk with one leg off the ground reflected behind him. &amp;ldquo;The week has come and gone. What is Jack saying about this inability to produce his son?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Well, he is telling me he hasn&amp;rsquo;t had time to meet with him. He says he&amp;rsquo;s been busy with school and Nick hasn&amp;rsquo;t been at home to answer his calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 14</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter14/</guid>
      <description>1985.01.21 Danny
Danny hung up the phone and looked across the kitchen at Jeannie. Her worry and concern reflected his own. &amp;ldquo;Was that the sheriff,&amp;rdquo; she asked.
&amp;ldquo;It was, the men that Nick told us about our in town. They showed up early Sunday morning.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Are they coming here?&amp;rdquo; Her worry lines deepened and she couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but look out the window as she asked. &amp;ldquo;I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand who these guys are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 15</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter15/</guid>
      <description>Nick watched the side-view mirror of the motorcycle as the hotels of Las Vegas shrank. It was still too cold to drive at night which meant he was making his trip back to Medford in a single 10-hour drive. The sun was low on the horizon, having only been out for an hour. That was long enough to warm the air and chase away the overnight frost.
US Highway 95 stretched out in front of him razor straight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 16</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter16/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I was beginning to think you weren&amp;rsquo;t as smart as I gave you credit for,&amp;rdquo; Holland said from the shadows as the sheriff stepped into the entryway of the barn.
&amp;ldquo;Well, I didn&amp;rsquo;t see much reason to come poking around in the middle of the night. Where are the Avery&amp;rsquo;s?&amp;rdquo; The sheriff hadn&amp;rsquo;t moved any further into the barn, his hand rested on his sidearm. Holland stepped out into a square patch of sunlight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 17</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter17/</guid>
      <description>Sonny Pera was in a bad mood as he leaned against the cream-colored stucco wall of the McDonald&amp;rsquo;s. He stared out across the six lanes of traffic on the Las Vegas strip as he dug in his jacket pocket for a cigarette. Everything in this city looks shabby during the day. Without the bright lights to distract your eye layers of city dirt desert dust stand out everywhere. Across the street, the Silver City marquee showed sunbleached and rife with cracks and rust spots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 18</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter18/</guid>
      <description>The driver took I-10 from the airport to N. Claiborne Ave. The car rode in the shadows of the causeway until they reached Esplanade. It was a wide dived street with the north and south lanes separated by a lush green park-like strip down the center.
Rows of live oak trees towered over the median, throwing shade out with their sprawling limbs. A dirt path ran between the trees, conjuring images of an older time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 19</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter19/</guid>
      <description>Nick drove his bike through the Marigny, taking Charters Street down into the upper 9th Ward. The road followed a series of ports on the Mississippi, all with rail access. He followed the tracks to Pauline Street, pulling to a stop around the corner in front of a long single-story warehouse. The concrete building was whitewashed with a rusting iron gate in front of a lonely man-door. There appeared to be no other entryway into the building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 20</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter20/</guid>
      <description>Sonny sat staring at the gilded double doors of rich black walnut positioned not quite behind the reception area. Outside of the elevators, the room opened into hallways on both sides, running the length of the building. The seating area itself consisted of three large couches with four matching leather armchairs. Brass accented the deep brown furniture and formed three sides of a square, the open end facing a long wooden paneled countertop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 21</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter21/</guid>
      <description>She caught his eye again while serving drinks to the young men across the balcony. Her lips twisted into a grin as their eyes met. Something in the pit of Jack’s stomach twisted with delight. He knew she wanted to know more about him, a lot more. He looked around. The make-shift music hall was bereft of traditional adornment, no posters, no art, just blue-grey concrete walls.
Something about the underground venue had a rough and tumble vibe that added to Jack’s excitement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 22</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter22/</guid>
      <description>Nick stared at the duty sergeant staring back at him. Acquainted in the small town kind of way which happened behind the scenes in the French Quarter, he played to the familiarity. Hundreds of thousands of tourists breeze through places like these, their faces become a blur, copies of themselves, at once anonymous and familiar. When a face is seen for more than a few weeks changes to someone you recognize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 23</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter23/</guid>
      <description>Sonny ripped the phone out of the wall and threw it hard over the balcony. It bounced twice and skidded into the pool. His cheeks burned in his eyes stung. He couldn&amp;rsquo;t think, he needed to lash out at everything within reach. His body shook with the effort of control. He took a deep shuddering breath and stood up straight, swallowing hard.
He was still standing, staring out at the green grass between the house and the pool when Aimee found him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 24</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter24/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Huh, that&amp;rsquo;s true. I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen Dr. Farouk draw blood himself,&amp;rdquo; Christoph observed. &amp;quot; I wonder if he&amp;rsquo;s squeamish about it? That&amp;rsquo;s a funny thought.&amp;quot; he pushed a cotton ball into the back of Nick&amp;rsquo;s elbow as you withdrew the needle. &amp;ldquo;All set,&amp;rdquo; he said while labeling the vials before sliding them neatly into the vertical test tube rack on the top shelf of the mini-fridge. &amp;ldquo;We will be taking more samples after today&amp;rsquo;s tests, same as yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 25</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter25/</guid>
      <description>Jack leaned back into the cushions of the wicker beach chair and sipped his Mai Tai. He had an unbleached, wide-brimmed straw hat and an oversize pair of Elton John sunglasses as much to hide the bruising on his face as to protect him from the sun. Aimee left him with an open tab to wait. &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t get too drunk. We still have things to do,&amp;rdquo; she had told him. But that seemed hours ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 26</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter26/</guid>
      <description>Aimee watched as Andres intercepted Jack by gather move into a one-arm walking hug. The way her cousin anticipated her need for privacy made her smile. Although in Jack&amp;rsquo;s defense, he seemed to get along well with the boys now that they had eliminated the pressure of trying to keep up with them. Jack threw one forlorn look over his shoulder as Andres hustled him down the path away from the cemetery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 27</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter27/</guid>
      <description>Sonny’s heart was pushing against his lungs with every beat. It was hard to breathe, let alone force himself to knock on the door. The brass plaque on the door read; Dr. Cynthia Blackwell, and mocked everything Randal Senior stood for. With a swallow, he rapped his knuckles under the nameplate with a rapid-fire tot-tot-tot. There were plenty of reasons to hide his uncertainty. He smoothed his lapels and straightened the tie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 28</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter28/</guid>
      <description>Nobody used the loading docks on the backside of the hospital. The entire North wing was officially closed, abandoned really by the fifth sixth and seventh floors of the North wing made up the semipermanent research facility led by Dr. Blackwell. But she had official roles here, as did Sonny and Farouk. Which meant there was no reason for the white Ford sedan to be this far down the service road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 29</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter29/</guid>
      <description>Holland watched Darren shake off the paramedic and stumble to the back of his car after the tow truck dropped back on flat ground. It had been hard not to finish the big man off as he lay sprawled and stunned in the road. If their situations had been reversed, he knew Horne wouldn’t hesitate to pull the trigger. When looking down at him helplessly in the road, Holland couldn’t bring himself to do it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 30</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter30/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m proud of you,&amp;rdquo; Aimee told him. &amp;ldquo;Getting Jack out of danger was the right thing to do.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Thanks, I think. I do feel relieved, kinda lighter, ya know?&amp;rdquo; Sonny responded.
&amp;ldquo;So what now? Do you have to go straight back to work?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Maybe not right away. What did you have in mind?&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty hungry, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to your place and get cleaned up to go out. Do you think that little place next to the river you took me to last time is open on Tuesdays?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 31</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter31/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter31/</guid>
      <description>Nick was staring at him, a crooked smile playing on his lips. “What you on about,” Holland asked.
“Nothing, I was just wishing there was some way to get to you right away.” He replied. Nick’s gaze had lost focus, and he was staring at something only he could see.
“When you mean right away?”
“I mean, we fucked this timeline. I have to go back. With everything we’ve learned about the Parra family and their motivations you know they won’t give up, ever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 32</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/chapter32/</guid>
      <description>“I only need two that have been initiated to take the stone from him, and I have Dr. Farouk here already, gentlemen,” the voice was muffled, distorted, and yet still carried, echoing through the stairwell. Nick guessed what Randall was driving at and broke from the safety of his corner to crash down the stairs. Randall was still yelling into the PA system. Nick ignored him to concentrate on not tripping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epilogue</title>
      <link>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/epilogue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.originathan.com/chapters/epilogue/</guid>
      <description>Something was terribly wrong.
Nick’s head was imploding in a massive bear trap of pain. Waves of nausea threatened to spill his stomach. Vertigo tore away all references. Then, all at once, the pain from the bullet and the rebirth faded away. He was getting better at this.
Nick rolled over onto his hands and knees, careful not to squish the little black schnauzer that had been trying to climb onto his chest.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
